<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<sop>
    <intro>People take summer and winter classes for a variety of reasons including earning credits toward graduating early, catching up, getting ahead, adding a major or minor, staying in Blacksburg, lightening the course load for fall and spring, or participating in study abroad. Depending on the class, it could be offered online, on campus, or both. If you are a potential student for these sessions, whether you are currently at Virginia Tech or not, you are in the right place. In the next section you will find instructions for registering for these classes. 
    </intro>
    <sessions>
        
        <session>
            <url>summer.html</url>
            <sessiontitle>Summer Session I and II</sessiontitle>
            <welcome>There are two six-week Summer Sessions at Virginia Tech that offer a variety of classes in different departments, and you can register for up to 12 credits over the summer as an undergraduate or 18 as a graduate student. Some classes are offered only in Summer Session I and others are only in Summer Session II so keep that in mind as you are planning your summer break and course schedule.</welcome>
            <tasks>
                <!--below is Task 1-->
                <task>
                    <tasktitle>How to prepare for registration (Virginia Tech students)</tasktitle>
                    <staging>These are the steps Virginia Tech students should take to prepare for registering for classes.</staging>
                    <ingredients>
                        <ingredient>
                            <item>Computer with Internet connection</item>
                        </ingredient>
                        <ingredient>
                            <item>Hokie SPA Login information</item>
                        </ingredient>
                    </ingredients>
                    <steps>
                        <step><action>Log in to your Hokie SPA account using your PID and password.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Select "Registration and Schedule" from the Hokie SPA main menu.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click "Prepare for Registration" link.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Select the open term in which you are attempting to register.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click "Continue."</action></step>
                        <step><action>Complete each of the pre-registration requirements that appear on the screen.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Select the "Registration" tab in the navigation panel.</action></step>
                    </steps>
                    <summary>That is how Virginia Tech students should prepare to register for classes.</summary>
                </task>
                <!--Below is task 2-->
                <task>
                    <tasktitle>How to prepare for registration (non-Virginia Tech students)</tasktitle>
                    <staging>These are the steps non-Virginia Tech students should take to prepare for registering for classes.</staging>
                    <ingredients>
                        <ingredient>
                            <item>Computer with Internet connection</item>
                        </ingredient>
                    </ingredients>
                    <steps>
                        <step><action>Apply as a Non-Degree Seeking student at www.admissions.vt.edu/apply/apply-now.html</action></step>
                        <step><action>Follow the link to establish your account.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Follow the link to fill out an application as a Non-Degree seeking applicant.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Make corrections to the data.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Save and send your application.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Follow the instructions to pay the application fee online.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Check your email for a message from "admissions@vt.edu" with the subject "Virginia Tech Application Status Page."</action></step>
                        <step><action>Schedule a meeting with your academic advisor at your current institution.</action><note>Obtain permission to receive authorization to enroll in courses at Virginia Tech and transfer the credit to your home institution.</note></step>
                    </steps>
                    <summary>If you are not a Virginia Tech student, this is how you should prepare to register for classes.</summary>
                </task>
<!--Below is Task 3-->
                <task>
                    <tasktitle>How to find the CRN of the class(es) you need</tasktitle>
                    <staging>These are the steps for all students to find the CRN (course request number) of the class they need to take. You will need to use the CRN later in the process of registering. </staging>
                    <ingredients>
                        <ingredient><item>Computer with Internet connection</item></ingredient>
                        <ingredient><item>Hokie SPA Login information</item></ingredient>
                        <ingredient><item>Course number of the class (Ex: ENGL 3814)</item></ingredient>
                    </ingredients>
                    <steps>
                        <step><action>Log in to your Hokie SPA account using your PID and password.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click on the far-left tab in the navigation panel that says "Hokie Plus."</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click on "Timetable of Classes."</action></step>
                        <step><action>Locate the "Campus" field.</action><note>Select "Blacksburg" to see if the class you need is offered on campus. Select "Virtual" to see if the class you need is offered online.</note></step>
                        <step><action>Locate the "Term" field and select Summer I 2017 or Summer II 2017, depending on the term in which you need to take the class.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Locate the "Subject" field and select the department name for the class you are taking.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Locate the "Course Number" field and type in the four-digit number of the class.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click "FIND class sections."</action></step>
                        <step><action>Locate the CRN number for the course.</action><note>It will be all the way on the left-hand side of the course listing. This is what you will use to add the class.</note></step>
                    </steps>
                    <summary>That is how all students find the CRN for the class(es) they need to take.</summary>
                </task>
                <!--Below is Task 4-->
                <task>
                    <tasktitle>How to register for a class</tasktitle>
                    <staging>This is how all students register for a class at Virginia Tech.</staging>
                    <ingredients>
                        <ingredient><item>Computer with Internet connection</item></ingredient>
                        <ingredient><item>Hokie SPA Login information</item></ingredient>
                        <ingredient><item>CRN of the class</item></ingredient>
                    </ingredients>
                    <steps>
                        <step><action>Log in to your Hokie SPA account using your PID and password.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Select "Registration and Schedule" from the Hokie SPA main menu.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click the "Register for Classes" link.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Select the term you wish to register and click "Continue."</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click "Ok" on the financial and registration notice that appears.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click on the second tab labeled "Enter CRNs" and put in the CRN for the class.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Find the course and section you want to take and click the "Add" button to register.</action></step>
                    </steps>
                    <summary>These are the steps that all students should take to register for a class.</summary>
                </task>
                
            </tasks>
        </session>
     
     <!--This is the break between summer and winter sessions-->
     
        <session>
            <url>winter.html</url>
            <sessiontitle>Winter Session</sessiontitle>
            <welcome>Winter Session at Virginia Tech offers a variety of classes in different departments that are just like fall and spring, except condensed into a three-week period over winter break. You can take up to 6 credits during Winter Session.</welcome>
            <tasks>
                <!--Below is Task 5-->
                <task>
                    <tasktitle>How to drop a class</tasktitle>
                    <staging>You might need to drop a class after you have begun taking it. These are the instructions for how to officially drop a class in the system.</staging>
                    <ingredients>
                        <ingredient><item>Computer with Internet connection</item></ingredient>
                        <ingredient><item>Hokie SPA Login information</item></ingredient>
                    </ingredients>
                    <steps>
                        <step><action>Log in to your Hokie SPA account using your PID and password.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Select "Registration and Schedule" form the Hokie SPA main menu.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click "[Drop/Add] Register for Classes."</action></step>
                        <step><action>Select the term that the class is in and click "Continue."</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click the Action drop-down menu on the class you want to drop.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Select "Drop Web" on the menu.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click "Submit" on the bottom of the screen.</action></step>
                    </steps>
                    <summary>These are the steps to take to drop a class from Winter Session.</summary>
                </task> 
                <!--Below is Task 6a-->
                <task>
                    <tasktitle>How to pay for class(es) (Virginia Tech students)</tasktitle>
                    <staging>Virginia Tech students should follow these instructions to pay for classes.</staging>
                    <ingredients>
                        <ingredient><item>Computer with Internet connection</item></ingredient>
                        <ingredient><item>Hokie SPA Login information</item></ingredient>
                        <ingredient><item>Credit Card or Bank Account information, or another form of payment</item></ingredient>
                    </ingredients>
                    <steps>
                        <step><action>Log in to your Hokie SPA account using your PID and password.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click on the far-right tab in the navigation panel that says "Hokie Spa."</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click on "University Account Information."</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click "View and Pay e-Bill."</action></step>
                        <step><action>Locate "Make Payment" on the menu on the left side of the screen and click on it.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Type in a payment amount and choose a payment method from the drop-down menu.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click "Continue."</action></step>
                    </steps>
                    <summary>These are the steps for Virginia Tech students to pay for classes.</summary>
                </task>
                <!--Below is Task 6b-->
                <task>
                    <tasktitle>How to pay for class(es) (International Students)</tasktitle>
                    <staging>International students should follow these instructions to pay for classes.</staging>
                    <ingredients>
                        <ingredient><item>Computer with Internet connection</item></ingredient>
                        <ingredient><item>Hokie SPA Login information</item></ingredient>
                        <ingredient><item>Credit Card or Bank Account information, or another form of payment</item></ingredient>
                    </ingredients>
                    <steps>
                        <step><action>Visit the Virginia Tech Bursar's website at www.bursar.vt.edu.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Locate the "Payment Options for International Students" option.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click on "More" and follow the instructions on the screen.</action></step>
                    </steps>
                    <summary>These are the steps for International students to pay for classes.</summary>
                </task> 
                <!--Below is Task 7-->
                <task>
                    <tasktitle>How to apply for financial aid</tasktitle>
                    <staging>All students should follow these instructions to apply for financial aid.</staging>
                    <ingredients>
                        <ingredient><item>Computer with Internet connection</item></ingredient>
                    </ingredients>
                    <steps>
                        <step><action>Visit the FAFSA website at https://fafsa.ed.gov</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click "Start A New FAFSA" if you haven't filled one out before. Follow the instructions to fill out the forms.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click "Login" if you have filled out a FAFSA before. Fill out the forms to apply for the Summer or Winter term.</action></step>
                    </steps>
                    <summary>These are the steps for all students to apply for financial aid.</summary>
                </task>
                <!--Below is Task 8-->
                <task>
                    <tasktitle>How to withdraw from Winter Session</tasktitle>
                    <staging>All students who need to withdraw from Winter Session at Virginia Tech completely should follow these instructions using the online resignation form. </staging>
                    <ingredients>
                        <ingredient><item>Computer with Internet connection</item></ingredient>
                    </ingredients>
                    <steps>
                        <step><action>Visit the Virginia Tech registrar's website at www.registrar.vt.edu</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click on the middle tab labeled "Undergraduate Students" halfway down the page.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click on the "Forms" link.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Click on the "Student Withdrawal/Resignation Form" link to access the PDF.</action></step>
                        <step><action>Fill out the form and submit it to the Office of the University Registrar located in the Student Services Building at 800 Washington St., SW, Blacksburg, VA 24061.</action></step>
                    </steps>
                    <summary>These are the steps to withdraw from Winter Session at Virginia Tech completely.</summary>
                </task>      
                
            </tasks>
        </session>
        
    </sessions>
    
    
    
</sop>
